Abraham: Interpersonal skills are
the skills required to effectively
communicate, interact, and work
with individuals and groups alike
and these skills are important for
success especially in cyber security.
It is important to remember that cyber
security does not exist in isolation.
There is a strong human factor
involved just consider how many
breaches are initiated by ‘phishing.’
Nicole: Cyber security professionals
must be able to effectively interact
with all levels and departments
within an organisation and educate
other members of staff about cyber
security threats that affect the whole
organisation including themselves.
So, what exactly are interpersonal skills?
Abraham: Interpersonal skills include
—
• The ability to listen.
• Good verbal and non-verbal
communication abilities.
• The ability to question others and give
information in response to questioning.
• Respecting the views
and opinions of others.
• Putting across personal views
clearly and appropriately.
• Giving and receiving feedback
• The ability to clarify thoughts and views.
• Working well and collaborating with others
• Being self-aware
• And having empathy
Nicole: Cyber security is not just
an IT problem it affects everyone
in a company and organisation.
As more departments rely on digital
communication and technologies, then
cyber vulnerabilities will increase,
and cyber security professionals
will be called upon to resolve issues
across a range of areas making good
use of their interpersonal skills.